In my quest to watch every video game movie ever made, I just made it to one that I was really
dreading. And boy howdy did it hit me like a brick. A punishment I wouldn't wish upon my worst
enemy. Watching the Assassin's Creed movie. I have a theory that most people that watch this film
in theaters dumped it from their memories as a way of coping with the traumatic experience of
watching something so criminally boring. I think as a defense mechanism, the human body
voided the memory of this film's existence from a lot of people that were unfortunately
subjected to its horrors. Now the way I'm portraying it here makes it sound like it's one of the
worst movies ever made that's damn near unwatchable. And that's because it's not far off.
Not because I think it's objectively as bad as some of the other films I've already watched
like Silent Hill Revelations. There are definitely worst video game movies that have been made for
sure. But this one just does everything that nobody asks for. It is like the perfect epitome of
taking a property that you're adapting and then just wiping your ass with pretty much everything
to do with it. And I think what makes it more insulting is that there's glimmers of potential
throughout the movie like specifically with its action choreography. They do a really good job
of capturing the free running and parkour of the games as well as the combat of the games in this
movie. It's really flashy. It's really stylistic. Like they do a very good job at a pretty faithful
attempt at recreating that experience in a movie. I was very impressed with that. But everything
else around it is a complete disaster. By far its biggest sin is how boring the movie is. And
that's because instead of just you know as the games would set you up getting into the
animus, getting into the action and you are in the animus in the past doing all of your assassinship
instead of making that the focal point. Instead it's mainly about this tedious chore
of following our brooding aggressive protagonist, Cal, played by Michael Fossbinder, around
Abstergo as he talks to a lady who wants to end violence. She found the cure for violence. It's
the apple of Eden. Cal comes directly from the assassins bloodline. They find him. He's very
aggressive. Like he watched his father kill his mother when he was a kid and then he ran away.
His father was of course an assassin. He ran away and he grew up to be very violent and he fights
people. And he was on death row. He was getting killed because he killed the pimp. They make a point
at making that like what he was facing the death penalty for. She was like you're very violent.
And he says yeah you killed someone didn't you. You're a murderer. He's like well I mean I killed
a pimp. So because he murdered a pimp he was getting killed on death row and then the
temple are coming in and saving because they recognize that he's got the blood and they need him
to jack into the animus so they can go into the past and find the apple of Eden through him.
And they have all of Abstergo's set up with all of these other adjacent assassins in there that they
have been exploring to try and find clues but they need Cal. And Cal is just brooding and he
sometimes makes wise cracks but he's just so boring. Everything that happens in Abstergo is a snooze
fest. And it's really some weird decisions they made with the animus itself because instead of
just lying down in the animus they make it a giant claw. Literally like my gamer sub's claw machine
it is a giant claw that picks him up and does this with him like Gai rates him around for all of his
parkour maneuvers and it like thrusts him into a wall as he's like going back to the past.
I don't really get the point in this movie is entirely reliant on Lin's Flair to obstruct your
view of its CGI. It's a huge budget film but for some reason it seems really shy about showing
you its visual effects so that claw you never even get a clear picture of because it is constantly
like a fucking solar flare hitting your retinas like your peepers getting melted like that guy from
SpongeBob when the bald head shines in his direction. I don't know why they would even bother
changing the animus to something more intricate like that when they're not even going to show you
it and it also doesn't even matter it does not do anything it doesn't really change anything it's
just goofy and silly it's like they really wanted to make like some deep sci-fi spin off the
animus even though it's already very like deep tech I don't know I really don't know what they
thought they were cooking there but they fucking burnt that dish for sure. But when you finally do get
into 15th century Spain with one of Cal's ancestors it's really fine like the park where I said
looks good the action is actually pretty impressive the story sucks I don't think it's even worth
diving into the narrative here the story and the writing are trocious I think most of you know this
by now I am not the biggest Assassin's Creed enthusiast I am one of its most adamant haters I
am a D1 Assassin's Creed not enjoyer I am constantly screaming it from the mountaintops I have not
liked Assassin's Creed in about a decade like Black Flag I know it's a really cold take but Black
Flag was the last one I liked and I didn't even like that as much as everyone else seemed to I just
don't like the franchise it's not for me I don't I don't have any problem with people liking it though
that's totally fine it's just not for me anymore I find it to just be really not fun so right away
this movie already had a tall mountain to climb in regards to my personal taste but everything
they did here narratively was so much worse than any of the Assassin's Creed games and I've played
pretty much all of them I always give them a fair shake for the most part I don't know why they
wouldn't just take one of the story lines that had already been established through so many of these
games it would have been far easier and it would have made a lot more sense than what they tried to
conjure up with this dog shit it is a disaster like I said the Templars want to cure violence they
found the cure to aggression with the apple of Eden which takes away free will their whole plan
is get rid of free will so we can control them and there's no longer any violence and the lead
scientist that the Templars is someone that you grow kind of sympathetic with like oh seems like
she might start to realize is a bad idea like oh maybe the Templar can't be trusted with something
so powerful her motivation makes sense her mother was killed by an assassin now she wants to find
the apple of Eden to make sure that kind of tragedy doesn't happen anybody else fast forward
through the adventures of finding the apple of Eden it's really underwhelming like everything
that happened in the enemies with action was cool but everything that happened story wise was
really silly because it turns out the apple of Eden was with Christopher Columbus the whole time
Christopher Columbus was associated with the assassins and he held the apple of Eden in his grave
so when the Templar learned that they just go to where Christopher Columbus was buried and just
asked for they're like oh the apple of Eden yeah it's right over here we got it it's in this box
actually like it was just it was just in their desk the whole time right under their nose this
entire time it was so lame and speaking of lame the entire character arc of cow sucks major
weiner so cow's dad kills his mom right in front of him and it's you know that really fucks him
up understandably so so he spends his whole life like just being mean and aggressive and he like
hates his dad once his dad to die so like his final words on the deathbed were tell my father
I'll see him in hell that's what he says it's so edgy it's so grossly cringe but we do get to
see his dad abstergo actually has his dad there because they were using him to find more information
on the apple of Eden so then he gets to meet his dad he's like papa I hate you and he's like
I get that is it because I killed your mother I did do that I didn't kill your mother but I did
it for her own good the assassins must protect the apple of Eden we have a creed we must uphold
the assassins creed and cow has the hidden blade to him and he's like if you're gonna kill me cow
just do it I do deserve it and he's like do it yourself and gives him the blade so that's like
their closure moment and then eventually everything goes tits up after they learned about the
apple of Eden all the assassins gang up with cow to rise up against abstergo so they can't get the
apple of Eden and take away free will and cow's dad he has his hero moment where everyone's rising up
including including cow's dad and cow's dad kills one guy while he was like looking in the corner
Blair Witch style he turns around kills one guy and then immediately just gets ganked like the other
three dudes stab him a bunch and he just dies and that's the last you ever see a cow's dad
right I don't know what the point of even bringing him back was he added nothing truly a waste
and also the entire like rising up against abstergo was super weird because all the abstergo
employees all the security like they make a point of saying it was like a nine trillion dollar
operation with the animus and all the abstergo like henchmen and all their hired muscle and yet
not a single one of them has a gun in fact the only weapons abstergo has are the weapons the
assassins are proficient in crossbows knives swords and hidden blades that's all they have and keep
in mind the abstergo employees they are not assassins they're just hired hands but you would expect
them to have some fucking guns not a single gun the only projectile up and they have his crossbows
and they don't even use that only the assassins get that they literally have that there just so
the assassins can make sure they're fully equipped to rise up against them I don't know what the
plan was it was so fucking wacky anyway though the movie ends with them getting the apple back and
to get the apple back at cal ended up killing that lady's dad I forgot both of their names they
were just so underwhelming I do not remember those character names but the scientist girl she
actually saw cows flashback or rather his synchronization with the bloodline of the assassins
so she saw all of the other assassins that cow was seeing and one of them was her one of her ancestors
was actually an assassin meanwhile she is now a Templar scientist and you think that this is the
moment where they're planted the breadcrumb that she's going to turn and she's going to be the one
to stop her father from taking away free will with the apple but in fact all it is is her father gets
the apple and she's talking to him like papa I don't like what you're about to do with this
and he's like I understand but thanks for writing my speech this one's for you so then he goes
out there into the all the Templar like the whole organization he's like I have the apple of Eden
it's right here the sacred apple of Eden free will is gone we can control free will in those peskiest
ascans are a vanquished once I use this apple of Eden and then cal approaches the scientist lady
and he's like you know what I have to do right and she's like yeah so then he walks by her and then
just kills her dad no no issue at all no hiccups just walks up kills the dad and then takes the
apple and then the scientist lady goes up to the dad's body while his corpse is cold she sheds a
tear and then she decides that she wants to double down and get the apple back and kill every
assassin we must eradicate the assassins and take away free will even though just minutes ago she
had a huge issue with what her dad was about to do meanwhile she is now completely flip flopped
once the exact same thing what the fuck and I don't know what they were trying to set up but they
didn't follow through on it I feel like they probably were going in a different direction at some
point and then just said fuck it just ship it and it just doesn't connect it doesn't really work
nothing in the movie really works aside from it aside from its action that's the only saving
grace of this film and it doesn't save it this movie is so boring I already didn't like
assassins create as a property and this made me like it even less I like it it's just insulting
it's bad it's not good that's really about it tear